## Alexander Evers

2131 East Norris St Philadelphia, PA 19125 (215) 589-8128 aevers365@gmail.com

# **Summary**

Dedicated worker and disciplined learner seeks to expand on digital product design and development skills, as well as technology and multimedia experience gained through contracting work and 4 years of successful employment at The StayWell Company to cultivate a growth-oriented career at the intersection of design and technology.

## **Professional Experience**

## The StayWell Company – Strategic Partnerships Division, Yardley, PA

## **Product Analyst**

January 2017 – December 2018

- Author content and logic within a proprietary web platform to create interactive care programs for patients with chronic illnesses and conditions
- Author sample programs to demonstrate product capabilities to prospective clients and partners.
- Help to conceptualize, implement, and test new features and enhancements to our company's platform
- Develop Micro Learning Units to deliver dynamic, interactive content to users
- Assist in the development of product strategies designed to meet the needs of users and the business
- Find and report bugs during the QA phases of development for multiple products

#### **Multimedia Producer**

February 2016 – January 2017

- Contributed to the conceptualization and development of multimedia assets, including photos, videos, and animations
- Assisted in a large-scale rebranding initiative for a newly acquired video library
- Continued to provide graphic design support for various brochures and marketing collateral
- Filled various production crew roles on photo and video sets

## **Content Manager**

January 2014 – February 2016

- Copywriting, content development, asset management, UX conceptualization, and QA on the award-winning American Red Cross Advanced Child Care Training e-learning course
- Development and design of a rebranded marketing collateral suite for the American Lung Association health education print portfolio
- Creation of long-form and short-form marketing copy for the American Heart Association patient education print portfolio
- Editorial and production work on multiple photo and video sets including securing talent release forms, coordinating locations and securing props/wardrobe

1

- Project management support for development of Louisiana State Public Health Department mobile app, including UI/UX input and Balsamiq wireframing
- Graphic design support on brochures and collateral for American Heart Association, American Lung Association and National Sleep Foundation product lines

#### **Independent Contractor – Editorial Department**

June 2013 – January 2014

- Continued to leverage internship experience and aquatics background to support the update of the American Red Cross Swimming and Water Safety training program
- Completed various assignments as needed for both print-based and e-learning programs
- Worked on the sets of various photo and video shoots
- Worked in an electronic environment to create digital products and e-learning courses

## Intern – Editorial Department

May 2012 – August 2012, January 2013

- Leveraged aquatics background to assist in update of American Red Cross Aquatics training program portfolio:
  - Wrote content and voiceover scripts for Lifeguarding e-learning refresher program
  - o Designed instructional activities for various online aquatics programs
  - Helped coordinate location, talent and wardrobe and provided subject matter technical support during several photo/video shoots for e-learning courses
  - Reviewed Lifeguarding video footage with staff editors to integrate into training program
  - Copyedited Swimming and Water Safety training participant and instructor manuals
- Copyedited mobile app content for American Red Cross First Aid/CPR/AED and Pet First Aid programs
- Performed editorial assessments of current products in anticipation of new edition releases
- Organized and managed art/content assets and completed stock photo research for products in development

#### Skills

- Adobe Creative Suite Photoshop, Lightroom, InDesign, Illustrator, Premiere Pro, After Effects, Muse
- Software testing
- Content and logic authoring
- Basic HTML/CSS, JS, and JSON
- Balsamiq wireframing software
- Education

Bachelor of Arts (Cum Laude) – English Bloomsburg University of Pennsylvania

Minor: Professional Writing

GPA: 3.5

High School Diploma Souderton Area High School, Souderton PA

- Content development
- Asset management
- DSLR photography
- Copywriting

2

• Graphic design

May 2013

June 2009

References are available upon request